[
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Bihar State Formation Day",
        "answer": "22nd March 1912",
        "choices": [
            "22nd March 1912",
            "22nd March 1913",
            "12nd March 1922",
            "23rd March 1912"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "North most latitude of Bihar",
        "answer": "27 deg 31 min 15 sec N",
        "choices": [
            "27 deg 31 min 15 sec N",
            "24 deg 20 min 10 sec N",
            "83 deg 19 min 50 sec N",
            "88 deg 17 min 40 sec N"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "South most latitude of Bihar",
        "answer": "24 deg 20 min 10 sec N",
        "choices": [
            "24 deg 20 min 10 sec N",
            "27 deg 31 min 15 sec N",
            "83 deg 19 min 50 sec N",
            "88 deg 17 min 40 sec N"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "East most longitude of Bihar",
        "answer": "88 deg 17 min 40 sec E",
        "choices": [
            "88 deg 17 min 40 sec E",
            "27 deg 31 min 15 sec E",
            "83 deg 19 min 50 sec E",
            "24 deg 20 min 10 sec E"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "West most longitude of Bihar",
        "answer": "83 deg 19 min 50 sec E",
        "choices": [
            "83 deg 19 min 50 sec E",
            "27 deg 31 min 15 sec E",
            "88 deg 17 min 40 sec E",
            "24 deg 20 min 10 sec E"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "North-South extent of Bihar",
        "answer": "345 km",
        "choices": [
            "345 km",
            "453 km",
            "435 km",
            "543 km"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "East-West extent of Bihar",
        "answer": "483 km",
        "choices": [
            "483 km",
            "834 km",
            "384 km",
            "438 km"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Total area of Bihar",
        "answer": "94,163 sq km",
        "choices": [
            "94,163 sq km",
            "91,463 sq km",
            "96,143 sq km",
            "93,164 sq km"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Area of Bihar compared to area of India",
        "answer": "2.86 percent",
        "choices": [
            "2.86 percent",
            "3.28 percent",
            "8.32 percent",
            "2.38 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Height of Bihar above mean sea-level in feet",
        "answer": "173 ft",
        "choices": [
            "173 ft",
            "371 ft",
            "137 ft",
            "317 ft"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Height of Bihar above mean sea-level in meters",
        "answer": "53 m",
        "choices": [
            "53 m",
            "52 m",
            "51 m",
            "50 m"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Total number of Divisions in Bihar",
        "answer": 9,
        "choices": [
            9,
            8,
            10,
            7
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Total number of Districts in Bihar",
        "answer": 38,
        "choices": [
            38,
            39,
            37,
            36
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Total number of Sub-Divisions in Bihar",
        "answer": 101,
        "choices": [
            101,
            100,
            102,
            103
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Total number of Blocks in Bihar",
        "answer": 534,
        "choices": [
            534,
            535,
            533,
            532
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Total number of Panchayat in Bihar",
        "answer": 8406,
        "choices": [
            8406,
            8405,
            8407,
            8403
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "How many district of Bihar shares international boundary with Nepal",
        "answer": 7,
        "choices": [
            7,
            8,
            3,
            6
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Northern-most district of Bihar",
        "answer": "West Champaran",
        "choices": [
            "West Champaran",
            "Gaya",
            "Kishanganj",
            "Kaimur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Southern-most district of Bihar",
        "answer": "Gaya",
        "choices": [
            "Gaya",
            "West Champaran",
            "Kishanganj",
            "Kaimur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Eastern-most district of Bihar",
        "answer": "Kishanganj",
        "choices": [
            "Kishanganj",
            "West Champaran",
            "Gaya",
            "Kaimur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Western-most district of Bihar",
        "answer": "Kaimur",
        "choices": [
            "Kaimur",
            "West Champaran",
            "Gaya",
            "Kishanganj"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Area wise largest district of Bihar",
        "answer": "West Champaran",
        "choices": [
            "West Champaran",
            "Gaya",
            "Kaimur",
            "Rohtas"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Area wise smallest district of Bihar",
        "answer": "Sheohar",
        "choices": [
            "Sheohar",
            "Sheikhpura",
            "Arwal",
            "Jehanabad"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "District with highest rainfall in Bihar",
        "answer": "Kishanganj",
        "choices": [
            "Kishanganj",
            "Kaimur",
            "Araria",
            "Patna"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "District with least rainfall in Bihar",
        "answer": "Kaimur",
        "choices": [
            "Kaimur",
            "Kishanganj",
            "Araria",
            "Patna"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Average number of rainy days in Bihar in a year",
        "answer": "52.5 days",
        "choices": [
            "52.5 days",
            "53.5 days",
            "55.5 days",
            "51.5 days"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Official language of Bihar",
        "answer": "Hindi",
        "choices": [
            "Hindi",
            "Bhojpuri",
            "Maithili",
            "Magahi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "In which constitutional amendment Maithili was included in the 8th Schedule of Constitution",
        "answer": "92nd",
        "choices": [
            "92nd",
            "91st",
            "93rd",
            "90th"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "What is the population percentage of Bihar compared to India according to Census 2011",
        "answer": "8.6 percent",
        "choices": [
            "8.6 percent",
            "6.8 percent",
            "9.6 percent",
            "6.9 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "What is the population percentage density of Bihar according to Census 2011",
        "answer": "1,106 person per sq km",
        "choices": [
            "1,106 person per sq km",
            "1,006 person per sq km",
            "1,306 person per sq km",
            "1,206 person per sq km"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "District with highest population density in Bihar",
        "answer": "Sheohar",
        "choices": [
            "Sheohar",
            "Sheikhpura",
            "Patna",
            "Kaimur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "District with least population density in Bihar",
        "answer": "Kaimur",
        "choices": [
            "Kaimur",
            "Sheikhpura",
            "Patna",
            "Sheohar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Most populated district of Bihar",
        "answer": "Patna",
        "choices": [
            "Patna",
            "Kaimur",
            "Sheohar",
            "Sheikhpura"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Least populated district of Bihar",
        "answer": "Sheikhpura",
        "choices": [
            "Sheikhpura",
            "Patna",
            "Kaimur",
            "Sheohar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Sex Ratio of Bihar according to Census 2011",
        "answer": 918,
        "choices": [
            918,
            819,
            981,
            891
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Child Sex Ratio of Bihar according to Census 2011",
        "answer": 935,
        "choices": [
            935,
            918,
            953,
            943
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "District with highest sex ratio in Bihar",
        "answer": "Gopalganj",
        "choices": [
            "Gopalganj",
            "Munger",
            "Patna",
            "Rohtas"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "District with least sex ratio in Bihar",
        "answer": "Munger",
        "choices": [
            "Munger",
            "Gopalganj",
            "Patna",
            "Rohtas"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Literacy rate of Bihar according to Census 2011",
        "answer": "61.80 percent",
        "choices": [
            "61.80 percent",
            "68.10 percent",
            "81.60 percent",
            "86.10 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "District with highest literacy rate in Bihar",
        "answer": "Rohtas",
        "choices": [
            "Rohtas",
            "Patna",
            "Purnea",
            "Munger"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "District with lowest literacy rate in Bihar",
        "answer": "Purnea",
        "choices": [
            "Purnea",
            "Patna",
            "Rohtas",
            "Munger"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "What is the urbanisation rate of Bihar according to Census 2011",
        "answer": "11.29 percent",
        "choices": [
            "11.29 percent",
            "21.92 percent",
            "12.29 percent",
            "12.92 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Most urbanised district of Bihar",
        "answer": "Patna",
        "choices": [
            "Patna",
            "Vaishali",
            "Gaya",
            "Nalanda"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Least urbanised district of Bihar",
        "answer": "Munger",
        "choices": [
            "Munger",
            "Gopalganj",
            "Buxar",
            "Bhojpur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "What is the tribal population of Bihar compared to India according to Census 2011",
        "answer": "1.30 percent",
        "choices": [
            "1.30 percent",
            "1.68 percent",
            "1.03 percent",
            "1.86 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "What is the tribal population of Bihar compared to India according to Caste Survey 2022",
        "answer": "1.68 percent",
        "choices": [
            "1.68 percent",
            "1.30 percent",
            "1.03 percent",
            "1.86 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Rank of Bihar among all state & UTs of India in terms of Population",
        "answer": "3rd",
        "choices": [
            "3rd",
            "1st",
            "2nd",
            "4th"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Rank of Bihar among all state & UTs of India in terms of Area",
        "answer": "12th",
        "choices": [
            "12th",
            "11th",
            "13th",
            "10th"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Decadal population growth of Bihar till 2011",
        "answer": "25.42 percent",
        "choices": [
            "25.42 percent",
            "24.52 percent",
            "25.24 percent",
            "24.25 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Total seats in Bihar Vidhan Shabha (Legislative Assembly)",
        "answer": 243,
        "choices": [
            243,
            234,
            245,
            254
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Total seats in Bihar Vidhan Parishad (Legislative Council)",
        "answer": 75,
        "choices": [
            75,
            85,
            65,
            95
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Total Lok Shabha seats from Bihar",
        "answer": 40,
        "choices": [
            40,
            35,
            45,
            50
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Total Rajya Shabha seats from Bihar",
        "answer": 16,
        "choices": [
            16,
            15,
            14,
            18
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Who was the first Governor of Bihar post independence",
        "answer": "Shri Jairam Daulatram",
        "choices": [
            "Shri Jairam Daulatram",
            "Shri Krishna Sinha",
            "Shri Rajendra Prasad",
            "Shri Arif Mohammad Khan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Who was the first Chief Minister of Bihar",
        "answer": "Shri Krishna Sinha",
        "choices": [
            "Shri Krishna Sinha",
            "Shri Jairam Daulatram",
            "Shri Rajendra Prasad",
            "Shri Arif Mohammad Khan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Bihar state is situated in the north of",
        "answer": "Tropic of Cancer",
        "choices": [
            "Tropic of Cancer",
            "Tropic of Capricon",
            "Equator",
            "Artic Circle"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "In which district of Bihar Dharwad period rocks are found",
        "answer": "All of these",
        "choices": [
            "All of these",
            "Munger",
            "Jamui",
            "Navada"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "In which district of Bihar Vindhyan series rocks are found",
        "answer": "Kaimur & Rohtas",
        "choices": [
            "Kaimur & Rohtas",
            "Kaimur",
            "Rohtas",
            "Gaya"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "When were rocks of Vindhyan series formed",
        "answer": "Pre-Cambrian Period",
        "choices": [
            "Pre-Cambrian Period",
            "Tertiary Period",
            "Quaternary Period",
            "Cambrian Period"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "When were rocks of Dharwad series formed",
        "answer": "Archeon",
        "choices": [
            "Archeon",
            "Protetozoic",
            "Milocene",
            "Pliestocene"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Tertiary rocks are found in which Himalayan series",
        "answer": "Shivalik",
        "choices": [
            "Shivalik",
            "Aravali",
            "Lesser Himalaya",
            "Greater Himalaya"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The Kaimur or Rohtas plateau is part of",
        "answer": "Vindhya",
        "choices": [
            "Vindhya",
            "Aravali",
            "Satpuda",
            "Dharwad"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Kaimur plateau is seperated from Chhota-Nagpur plateau by which river",
        "answer": "Son",
        "choices": [
            "Son",
            "Mahananda",
            "Ganga",
            "Falgu"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "New Alluvium soil is also known as",
        "answer": "Khadar",
        "choices": [
            "Khadar",
            "Bhangar",
            "Terai",
            "Keral-Keval"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Terai Soil is found along which border of Bihar",
        "answer": "Northern",
        "choices": [
            "Northern",
            "Southern",
            "Eastern",
            "Western"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Peidmont Swamp soil is found in which district of Bihar",
        "answer": "West Champaran",
        "choices": [
            "West Champaran",
            "Rohtas",
            "Kaimur",
            "Gaya"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "What do we extract from Pyrite mineral",
        "answer": "Sulphur",
        "choices": [
            "Sulphur",
            "Asbestos",
            "Sand",
            "Tungusten"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Pyrite is mainly found in which district of Bihar",
        "answer": "Rohtas",
        "choices": [
            "Rohtas",
            "Jamui",
            "Samstipur",
            "Banka"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which mineral is also known as Fool's Gold",
        "answer": "Pyrite",
        "choices": [
            "Pyrite",
            "Bauxite",
            "Hematite",
            "Quartzite"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where is Gold reserve of Bihar",
        "answer": "Jamui",
        "choices": [
            "Jamui",
            "Purnea",
            "Bhagalpur",
            "Munger"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "According to Koppen climate classification, Bihar falls under which category",
        "answer": "Cwa",
        "choices": [
            "Cwa",
            "Cfb",
            "Bwh",
            "Csc"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The most famous river for changing its route in Bihar is",
        "answer": "Kosi",
        "choices": [
            "Kosi",
            "Bagmati",
            "Gandak",
            "Mahananda"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which river flows from west to east in the middle of Bihar",
        "answer": "Ganga",
        "choices": [
            "Ganga",
            "Bagmati",
            "Gandak",
            "Mahananda"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "State the total length of Ganga in kms",
        "answer": "2525 km",
        "choices": [
            "2525 km",
            "5050 km",
            "2550 km",
            "5025 km"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "What is the length of Ganga within territory of Bihar",
        "answer": "445 km",
        "choices": [
            "445 km",
            "545 km",
            "345 km",
            "245 km"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where is the origin of the river Ganga",
        "answer": "Uttrakhand",
        "choices": [
            "Uttrakhand",
            "Uttar Pradesh",
            "Himachal Pradesh",
            "West Bengal"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Ganga river first enters in which district of Bihar from Uttar Pradesh",
        "answer": "Buxar",
        "choices": [
            "Buxar",
            "Saran",
            "Bhojpur",
            "Siwan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which of the following rivers decide the borders of Bihar and Uttar Pradesh",
        "answer": "All of these",
        "choices": [
            "All of these",
            "Ganga",
            "Gandak",
            "Karmanasha"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The river Ganga touches how many districts of Bihar",
        "answer": 12,
        "choices": [
            12,
            11,
            10,
            13
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which district of Bihar touches the river Ganga the longest",
        "answer": "Patna",
        "choices": [
            "Patna",
            "Munger",
            "Bhagalpur",
            "Katihar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The river Ganga terminates in",
        "answer": "Bay of Bengal",
        "choices": [
            "Bay of Bengal",
            "Indian Ocean",
            "Pacific Ocean",
            "Arabian Sea"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which river enters into Ganga 10 kms away from Danapur near west Maner",
        "answer": "Sone",
        "choices": [
            "Sone",
            "Punpun",
            "Falgu",
            "Gandak"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Origin of river Ghagra",
        "answer": "Nepal",
        "choices": [
            "Nepal",
            "Uttar Pradesh",
            "Uttarakhand",
            "Himachal Pradesh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which of the following rivers is also known as Saryu",
        "answer": "Ghaghra",
        "choices": [
            "Ghaghra",
            "Gandak",
            "Punpun",
            "Son"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Ghaghra river merges with Ganga in which district of Bihar",
        "answer": "Saran",
        "choices": [
            "Saran",
            "Vaishali",
            "Bhojpur",
            "Buxar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The river Gandak enters in which district of Bihar first",
        "answer": "West Champaran",
        "choices": [
            "West Champaran",
            "Gopalganj",
            "Buxar",
            "Siwan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "In which district Valmiki Nagar Barrage has been built",
        "answer": "West Champaran",
        "choices": [
            "West Champaran",
            "Gopalganj",
            "Buxar",
            "Siwan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Valmiki Nagar Barrage is built upon which river",
        "answer": "Gandak",
        "choices": [
            "Gandak",
            "Son",
            "Kosi",
            "Ganga"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Name of the world famous fair held at the confluence of Gandak river",
        "answer": "Harihar Kshetra Mela",
        "choices": [
            "Harihar Kshetra Mela",
            "Pitrpaksha Mela",
            "Makar Sankranti Mela",
            "Babadham Mela"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "World's largest cattle fair is organised at confluence of which river",
        "answer": "Gandak",
        "choices": [
            "Gandak",
            "Son",
            "Kosi",
            "Ganga"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which river flows in the eastern part parallel to the river Gandak",
        "answer": "Budhi Gandak",
        "choices": [
            "Budhi Gandak",
            "Saryu",
            "Karmanasha",
            "Bagmati"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which river has it's origin in Chautarva Chaur near Vishambharpur under Someshwar series hills",
        "answer": "Budhi Gandak",
        "choices": [
            "Budhi Gandak",
            "Gandak",
            "Bagmati",
            "Kosi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which of the following rivers has shifted 150 kms from east to west in the last 200 years",
        "answer": "Kosi",
        "choices": [
            "Kosi",
            "Gandak",
            "Bagmati",
            "Mahananda"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "At which place the river Kosi forms a delta before merging with river Ganga",
        "answer": "Kursela",
        "choices": [
            "Kursela",
            "Bhagalpur",
            "Chhapra",
            "Hajipur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which of the following is the major tributary of Budhi-Gandak",
        "answer": "Bagmati",
        "choices": [
            "Bagmati",
            "Gandak",
            "Punpun",
            "Kosi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The origin of Bagmati has occurred in Nepal from which mountain range",
        "answer": "Mahabharat",
        "choices": [
            "Mahabharat",
            "Annapurna",
            "Aravali",
            "Someshwar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which river enters in Terai area after passing through Mahabharat range in Nepal",
        "answer": "Budhi-Gandak",
        "choices": [
            "Budhi-Gandak",
            "Kamala",
            "Gandak",
            "Punpun"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Ancient name of river Kosi",
        "answer": "Kaushiki",
        "choices": [
            "Kaushiki",
            "Saptaprabha",
            "Keshaki",
            "Kaushik"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "All the seven currents of Kosi merge at which place where it also known as Sapta Kosi",
        "answer": "Triveni (Nepal)",
        "choices": [
            "Triveni (Nepal)",
            "Balmiki Nagar",
            "Rajgir",
            "Pavapuri"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which of the following river is also known as Bihar ka shok",
        "answer": "Kosi",
        "choices": [
            "Kosi",
            "Mahananda",
            "Gandak",
            "Son"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Mount Everest and Kanchenjunga falls under catchement area of which river",
        "answer": "Kosi",
        "choices": [
            "Kosi",
            "Mahananda",
            "Gandak",
            "Son"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which of the following rivers is a river of the east following through North Bihar",
        "answer": "Mahananda",
        "choices": [
            "Mahananda",
            "Kamala",
            "Bagmati",
            "Son"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which river determines the borders of Bengal & Bihar",
        "answer": "Mahananda",
        "choices": [
            "Mahananda",
            "Kamala",
            "Bagmati",
            "Son"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Origin of which river lies in Amarkantak in Madhya Pradesh",
        "answer": "Son",
        "choices": [
            "Son",
            "Bagmati",
            "Punpun",
            "Falgu"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which river is the longest flowing tributary of the Ganga in Southern Bihar",
        "answer": "Son",
        "choices": [
            "Son",
            "Karmanasha",
            "Punpun",
            "Falgu"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Son river first enters in which district of Bihar",
        "answer": "Rohtas",
        "choices": [
            "Rohtas",
            "Jamui",
            "Gaya",
            "Jehanabad"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "On which of the following rivers Indrapuri Barrage is located",
        "answer": "Son",
        "choices": [
            "Son",
            "Gandak",
            "Punpun",
            "Falgu"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "On the riverbed of which of the following rivers, Gautam Buddha attained awakening",
        "answer": "Falgu",
        "choices": [
            "Falgu",
            "Gandak",
            "Punpun",
            "Son"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where in Bihar, Pitrapaksha Mela is held",
        "answer": "Gaya",
        "choices": [
            "Gaya",
            "Patna",
            "Sonpur",
            "Bhagalpur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "In which of the following rivers, the ritual of Pind-dan is performed",
        "answer": "Falgu",
        "choices": [
            "Falgu",
            "Gandak",
            "Punpun",
            "Son"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which river gets divided in two parts in Jehanabad district near Barabar Hills",
        "answer": "Falgu",
        "choices": [
            "Falgu",
            "Karmanasha",
            "Punpun",
            "Son"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Origin of the river Punpun",
        "answer": "Chhota-Nagpur Plataeu",
        "choices": [
            "Chhota-Nagpur Plataeu",
            "Kaimur Hills",
            "Aravalli Hills",
            "Amarkantak Hills"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "At which place Punpun river merges with Ganga",
        "answer": "Fatuha",
        "choices": [
            "Fatuha",
            "Maner",
            "Chhapra",
            "Danapur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which river has its ancient name as Hiranyavah",
        "answer": "Son",
        "choices": [
            "Son",
            "Gandak",
            "Karmanasha",
            "Punpun"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which art form of Bihar has a sequential representation of stories, hence also known as scroll painting",
        "answer": "Manjusha Art",
        "choices": [
            "Manjusha Art",
            "Mithila Art",
            "Tikuli Art",
            "Sujini Embroidery"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Bihula-Bishahari Gatha is related to with art form of Bihar",
        "answer": "Manjusha Art",
        "choices": [
            "Manjusha Art",
            "Mithila Art",
            "Tikuli Art",
            "Sujini Embroidery"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Origin of Manjusha Art ",
        "answer": "Bhagalpur",
        "choices": [
            "Bhagalpur",
            "Madhubani",
            "Gaya",
            "Patna"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Origin of Tikuli Art",
        "answer": "Patna",
        "choices": [
            "Patna",
            "Madhubani",
            "Gaya",
            "Bhagalpur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which art form is also know as Firangi Kalam or as the white man's art",
        "answer": "Patna Kalam",
        "choices": [
            "Patna Kalam",
            "Kalamkari",
            "Patachitra",
            "Madhubani Painting"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The subject of these paintings were common man and their mundane routines, name the art form",
        "answer": "Patna Kalam",
        "choices": [
            "Patna Kalam",
            "Sujini Embroidery",
            "Manjusha Art",
            "Madhubani Painting"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where is Kakolat Waterfall located in Bihar",
        "answer": "Nawada",
        "choices": [
            "Nawada",
            "Rohtas",
            "Kaimur",
            "Munger"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where is Tutla Bhawani Waterfall located in Bihar",
        "answer": "Rohtas",
        "choices": [
            "Rohtas",
            "Nawada",
            "Kaimur",
            "Munger"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where is Telhar Kund Waterfall located in Bihar",
        "answer": "Kaimur",
        "choices": [
            "Kaimur",
            "Nawada",
            "Rohtas",
            "Munger"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where is Karakat Waterfall located in Bihar",
        "answer": "Kaimur",
        "choices": [
            "Kaimur",
            "Nawada",
            "Rohtas",
            "Munger"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where is Manjhar Kund located in Bihar",
        "answer": "Rohtas",
        "choices": [
            "Rohtas",
            "Nawada",
            "Kaimur",
            "Munger"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where is Dhua Kund located in Bihar",
        "answer": "Rohtas",
        "choices": [
            "Rohtas",
            "Nawada",
            "Kaimur",
            "Munger"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where is Kanwar Lake located in Bihar",
        "answer": "Begusarai",
        "choices": [
            "Begusarai",
            "Rohtas",
            "Kaimur",
            "Nawada"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "How may Ramsar sites are there in Bihar as of 2025",
        "answer": "Three",
        "choices": [
            "Three",
            "Four",
            "Two",
            "Five"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where is Muchalinda Lake in Bihar",
        "answer": "Bodhgaya",
        "choices": [
            "Bodhgaya",
            "Rohtas",
            "Kaimur",
            "Nawada"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where is Sarai Man Lake in Bihar",
        "answer": "West Champaran",
        "choices": [
            "West Champaran",
            "Bodhgaya",
            "Munger",
            "Rajgir"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where is Moti Jheel located in Bihar",
        "answer": "East Champaran",
        "choices": [
            "East Champaran",
            "West Champaran",
            "Munger",
            "Rajgir"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where is Pandu Pokhar located in Bihar",
        "answer": "Rajgir",
        "choices": [
            "Rajgir",
            "West Champaran",
            "Munger",
            "Rohtas"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where is Ghorakatora Lake located in Bihar",
        "answer": "Rajgir",
        "choices": [
            "Rajgir",
            "West Champaran",
            "Munger",
            "Rohtas"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which type of forest is found in Bihar",
        "answer": "Moist Deciduos",
        "choices": [
            "Moist Deciduos",
            "Dry Deciduos",
            "Moist Evergreen",
            "Dry Evergreen"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which is most abundantly found in forests of Bihar",
        "answer": "Sal",
        "choices": [
            "Sal",
            "Shisham",
            "Teak",
            "Kadamb"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "How much is the natural forest cover in Bihar",
        "answer": "7.27 percent",
        "choices": [
            "7.27 percent",
            "2.72 percent",
            "3.72 percent",
            "7.32 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "How many National Parks are there in Bihar",
        "answer": "One",
        "choices": [
            "One",
            "Two",
            "Zero",
            "Three"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Valmiki National Park is located in",
        "answer": "West Champaran",
        "choices": [
            "West Champaran",
            "East Champaran",
            "Bhagalpur",
            "Munger"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Vikramshila Gangetic Dolphin Wildlife Sanctuary is located in",
        "answer": "Bhagalpur",
        "choices": [
            "Bhagalpur",
            "Begusarai",
            "Patna",
            "Munger"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where is Bhimbandh Wildlife Sanctuary located in Bihar",
        "answer": "Munger",
        "choices": [
            "Munger",
            "Begusarai",
            "Patna",
            "Bhagalpur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where is Gautam Buddha Wildlife Sanctuary located in Bihar",
        "answer": "Gaya",
        "choices": [
            "Gaya",
            "Begusarai",
            "Patna",
            "Bhagalpur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where is Udaypur Wildlife Sanctuary located in Bihar",
        "answer": "West Champaran",
        "choices": [
            "West Champaran",
            "Begusarai",
            "Patna",
            "Bhagalpur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where is Nakti Dam located in Bihar",
        "answer": "Jamui",
        "choices": [
            "Jamui",
            "Begusarai",
            "Patna",
            "Bhagalpur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where is Nagi Dam located in Bihar",
        "answer": "Jamui",
        "choices": [
            "Jamui",
            "Begusarai",
            "Patna",
            "Bhagalpur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The name of the Hindi weekly which was the mouthpiece of the agrarian and peasant movements in Bihar in 1940 was",
        "answer": "Hunkar",
        "choices": [
            "Hunkar",
            "Lokmat",
            "Sarathi",
            "Leader"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Who was author of Hunkar - a Hindi weekly voicing for peasants in Bihar",
        "answer": "Swami Sahajanand Saraswati",
        "choices": [
            "Swami Sahajanand Saraswati",
            "Ram Manohar Lohia",
            "Jagadish Prasad",
            "Jayaprakash Narayan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Who was the first provisional premier of Bihar under Provincial Autonomy in 1937",
        "answer": "Mohammad Yunus",
        "choices": [
            "Mohammad Yunus",
            "Shri Krishna Sinha",
            "Ramsunder Singh",
            "Jagdal Chaudhary"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Who was the first premier of Bihar under Provincial Autonomy in 1937",
        "answer": "Shri Krishna Sinha",
        "choices": [
            "Shri Krishna Sinha",
            "Mohammad Yunus",
            "Ramsunder Singh",
            "Jagdal Chaudhary"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The first Indian National Congress session in Bihar after bcoming a separate province was held in",
        "answer": "Patna, 1912",
        "choices": [
            "Patna, 1912",
            "Gaya, 1922",
            "Patna, 1934",
            "Gaya, 1934"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The Indian National Congress Session of 1922 was held at which place in Bihar?",
        "answer": "Gaya",
        "choices": [
            "Gaya",
            "Patna",
            "Munger",
            "Bhagalpur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Who organised the Hindu Mela",
        "answer": "Nabagopal Mitra",
        "choices": [
            "Nabagopal Mitra",
            "Satyendranath Tagore",
            "Aurobindo Ghosh",
            "Rajnarayan Bose"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Who was the commissioner of Patna divison during the revolt of 1857?",
        "answer": "William Taylor",
        "choices": [
            "William Taylor",
            "H. C. Wake",
            "Brigadier Douglas",
            "R. P. Harrison"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Kunwar Singh returned to Jagdishpur Palace on",
        "answer": "23rd April 1858",
        "choices": [
            "23rd April 1858",
            "23rd April 1859",
            "26th April 1859",
            "26th April 1858"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "When did Kunwar Singh, leader of revolt of 1857 in Bihar, breathed his last?",
        "answer": "26th April 1858",
        "choices": [
            "26th April 1858",
            "23rd April 1859",
            "23rd April 1858",
            "26th April 1859"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Veer Kunwar Singh was the king of",
        "answer": "Jagadishpur",
        "choices": [
            "Jagadishpur",
            "Dheerpur",
            "Rampur",
            "Hamirpur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Who fought bravely against the British troops under Brigadier Douglas on 21 April, 1858 in Bihar?",
        "answer": "Kunwar Singh",
        "choices": [
            "Kunwar Singh",
            "Ujjal Sahi",
            "Surendra Sahi",
            "Jagdal Choudhary"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Name the revolutionary from Bihar who attended the meeting of Hindustan Socialist Republican Army in September, 1928",
        "answer": "Phanindra Nath Ghosh",
        "choices": [
            "Phanindra Nath Ghosh",
            "Bhagat Singh",
            "Ajay Ghosh",
            "Jyotindra Nath"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Patna was made capital of his state by",
        "answer": "Shershah Suri",
        "choices": [
            "Shershah Suri",
            "Alauddin Hussain Shah",
            "Ibrahim Lodi",
            "Prince Azim"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Who was the mentor of Birsa Munda?",
        "answer": "Anand Pandey",
        "choices": [
            "Anand Pandey",
            "Swami Sahajanand Saraswati",
            "Jatra Bhagat",
            "M. N. Roy"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "When was Birsa Munda born",
        "answer": "15th November 1875",
        "choices": [
            "15th November 1875",
            "15th November 1975",
            "15th November 1965",
            "15th November 1865"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Birsa Munda was captured in Chakradharpur, while asleep on",
        "answer": "3rd February 1900",
        "choices": [
            "3rd February 1900",
            "1st February 1900",
            "2nd February 1900",
            "4th February 1900"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Identify the region where Santhals declared their government in 1855-56",
        "answer": "Bhagalpur-Rajmahal",
        "choices": [
            "Bhagalpur-Rajmahal",
            "Munger-Bhagalpur",
            "Gaya-Munger",
            "Shahabad-Gaya"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The Bihar Herald was started in 1872 by",
        "answer": "Babu Guru Prasad Sen",
        "choices": [
            "Babu Guru Prasad Sen",
            "Munahi Surajmal",
            "Rai Roshan Lal",
            "Krishan Bhatt"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which was the first English newspaper published from Patna?",
        "answer": "The Bihar Herald",
        "choices": [
            "The Bihar Herald",
            "The Indian Mirror",
            "Searchlight",
            "Hindoo Patriot"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The revolt of 1857 affected many towns of Bihar, Which of the following is the correct sequence of the occurrence of revolt in various town of Bihar?",
        "answer": "Rohini > Patna > Muzaffarpur > Jagdishpur",
        "choices": [
            "Rohini > Patna > Muzaffarpur > Jagdishpur",
            "Muzaffarpur > Patna > Jagadishpur > Rohini",
            "Jagadishpur > Patna > Rohini > Muzaffarpur",
            "Patna > Muzaffarpur > Rohini > Jagadishpur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which leader of Bihar along with Mahatma Gandhi led the farmer's movement?",
        "answer": "Raj Kumar Shukla",
        "choices": [
            "Raj Kumar Shukla",
            "Rajendra Prasad",
            "Baba Ramchandra",
            "Rafi Ahmed Kidwai"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Raj Kumar Shukla was a resident of which village?",
        "answer": "Murali Bharahwa",
        "choices": [
            "Murali Bharahwa",
            "Murali Bheet",
            "Murali Kher",
            "Murali Dhir"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Who highlighted the plight of the peasants of Champaran by writing psedonyms like Dukhi, Dukhi Atma, Dukhi Hriday?",
        "answer": "Pir Mohaammed Munis",
        "choices": [
            "Pir Mohaammed Munis",
            "Rajendra Prasad",
            "Rajkumar Shukla",
            "Sahajanand Saraswati"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Who was the author of Biography of Kunwar Singh and Amar Singh",
        "answer": "Kalikinkar Datta",
        "choices": [
            "Kalikinkar Datta",
            "M. N. Roy",
            "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Sahajanand Saraswati"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Swami Sahajanand Saraswati published a magazine named",
        "answer": "Hunkar",
        "choices": [
            "Hunkar",
            "Jankranti",
            "Krishak Samachar",
            "Vidrohi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "One of the popular beliefs in Bihar during the Non-Cooperation Movement of 1920-22 was that they would be victorious because Gandhi",
        "answer": "was an accomplished politician",
        "choices": [
            "was an accomplished politician",
            "was the epitome of Dharma",
            "knew the way to defeat the English",
            "knew English"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "On which date Linlithgow ordered to fire on the mob of Patna and its surrounding during the August Revolution, 1942?",
        "answer": "11th August 1942",
        "choices": [
            "11th August 1942",
            "1st August 1942",
            "15th August 1942",
            "5th August 1942"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Dr. Rajendra Prasad, who was the first President of India, earlier held the position of",
        "answer": "Chairman of Patna Municipality",
        "choices": [
            "Chairman of Patna Municipality",
            "Chief Minister of Bihar",
            "Head Postmaster at Chapra",
            "Mayor of Patna"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where was the first Zila School of Bihar opened in 1835",
        "answer": "Patna",
        "choices": [
            "Patna",
            "Muzaffarpur",
            "Darbhanga",
            "Munger"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Who left Patna College with just 20 days remaining for his examination during the Non-Cooperation movement?",
        "answer": "Jai Prakash Narayan",
        "choices": [
            "Jai Prakash Narayan",
            "Rajendra Prasad",
            "Braj Kishore",
            "Shri Krishna Sinha"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Jubba Sahni, a freedom fighter belonged to which district of Bihar?",
        "answer": "Muzaffarpur",
        "choices": [
            "Muzaffarpur",
            "Bhagalpur",
            "Patna",
            "Sasaram"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Who led cultivators in Bihar during the Non-Cooperation Movement?",
        "answer": "Swami Vidyanand",
        "choices": [
            "Swami Vidyanand",
            "Shri Krishna Sinha",
            "Raj Kumar Shukla",
            "Sahajanand Saraswati"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Who led the peasant movement in the region of Darbhanga Raj?",
        "answer": "Swami Vidyanand",
        "choices": [
            "Swami Vidyanand",
            "Baba Ramchandra",
            "Vinoba Bhave",
            "Sahajanand Saraswati"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "During Salt Satyagraha, in Bihar, in addition to making salt, the people choose to oppose the government by opposing which tax?",
        "answer": "Chowkidari",
        "choices": [
            "Chowkidari",
            "Haathi",
            "Malba",
            "Development"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "When was the Salt Movement started in Bihar?",
        "answer": "12th March 1930",
        "choices": [
            "12th March 1930",
            "12th April 1930",
            "12th May 1930",
            "12th June 1930"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Famous sufi saint of Bihar Sharfuddin Maneri is related to which Sufi order?",
        "answer": "Firdausi",
        "choices": [
            "Firdausi",
            "Chisti",
            "Suhrawardi",
            "Kubrawi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Who was the first Muslim conqueror of Bihar?",
        "answer": "Bakhtiyar Khalji",
        "choices": [
            "Bakhtiyar Khalji",
            "Malik Ibrahim",
            "Iltutmish",
            "Ali Mardan Khalji"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Baba Thakur Das established which society in Patna?",
        "answer": "Ramakrishna Mission Society",
        "choices": [
            "Ramakrishna Mission Society",
            "Servants of India Society",
            "Seva Samiti",
            "Social Service League"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Who established the branch of Anushila Samiti at Patna in 1913",
        "answer": "Sachindra Nath Sanyal",
        "choices": [
            "Sachindra Nath Sanyal",
            "Bankim Chandra Mitra",
            "Raghubir Singh",
            "Baba Thakur Das"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Who established Swaraj Dal in Bihar",
        "answer": "Shri Krishna Sinha",
        "choices": [
            "Shri Krishna Sinha",
            "Bankim Chandra Mitra",
            "Ramlal Singh",
            "Rajendra Prasad"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Bihar Congress Socialist Party was formed in ",
        "answer": 1934,
        "choices": [
            1934,
            1939,
            1931,
            1930
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Bihar Socialist party was born in 1934 with its secretary",
        "answer": "Jayaprakash Narayan",
        "choices": [
            "Jayaprakash Narayan",
            "Acharya Narendra Dev",
            "Rambriksh Benipuri",
            "Karpoori Thakur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Who formed the Bihar Samajwadi Party in 1931",
        "answer": "Phoolan Prasad Verma & Jayaprakash Narayan",
        "choices": [
            "Phoolan Prasad Verma & Jayaprakash Narayan",
            "Phoolchand Tiwari & Rajendra Prasad",
            "Rajkumar Shukla & Swami Agnivesh",
            "Swami Sahajanand & Swami Yogananda"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "When was Bihar Samajwadi Party formed",
        "answer": 1931,
        "choices": [
            1931,
            1934,
            1939,
            1930
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Bihar Provincial Kisan Sabha was formed in",
        "answer": 1929,
        "choices": [
            1929,
            1934,
            1939,
            1930
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Who started the Kisan Sabha Movement in Bihar in 1929?",
        "answer": "Swami Sahajanand Saraswati",
        "choices": [
            "Swami Sahajanand Saraswati",
            "Raj Kumar Shukla",
            "Baikuntha Shukla",
            "Acharya Kripalani"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Name the left-wing leader of Bihar Provincial Kisan Sabha who popularised this in Bihar?",
        "answer": "karyanand Sharma",
        "choices": [
            "karyanand Sharma",
            "Wadhwa Ram",
            "P. C. Joshi",
            "Raj Kumar Shukla"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The first Indian Ministry in Bihar in 1937 came into existence under whose leadership?",
        "answer": "Md. Yunus",
        "choices": [
            "Md. Yunus",
            "Shri Krishna Sinha",
            "Wahab Ali",
            "G. S. Lal"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The elected Government of Bihar resigned in February 1938 for which reason?",
        "answer": "For the release of political prisoners",
        "choices": [
            "For the release of political prisoners",
            "the participation of India in war",
            "Satyagraha against the British at the call of Gandhi",
            "High taxes being imposed by British"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Who led the Ambari Satyagraha in 1939 in Bihar",
        "answer": "Rahul Sankrityayan",
        "choices": [
            "Rahul Sankrityayan",
            "Yadunandan Sharma",
            "Swami Sahajanand",
            "Swami Yoganand"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Who among the following was the leader of the first Congress Ministry in Bihar?",
        "answer": "Shri Krishna Sinha",
        "choices": [
            "Shri Krishna Sinha",
            "Abdul Bari",
            "Anugrah Narayan Sinha",
            "Jayaprakash Narayan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Gandhiji's Non-Cooperation movement urged people to avoid alcohol. This resulted in a serious loss of revenue for the government. The government of a province circulated a list of prominent individuals who drank alcohol as a device to persuade people to start drinking again. Name the province",
        "answer": "Bihar",
        "choices": [
            "Bihar",
            "Bombay",
            "Gujarat",
            "Andhra Pradesh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which of the following statement is correct about the Maharajas of Dumrao, Darbhanga and Hatwa during the revolt of 1857",
        "answer": "They helped the English with men and money",
        "choices": [
            "They helped the English with men and money",
            "They helped the English with men but not money",
            "They helped the English with only money but not men",
            "They opposed the English"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The word Bihar originally means",
        "answer": "Buddhist Monastery",
        "choices": [
            "Buddhist Monastery",
            "Land of Angels",
            "Arya Pradesh",
            "Land of Greenry"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "According to following districts, which one has larger area under dense deciduous forest cover?",
        "answer": "Paschim Champaran",
        "choices": [
            "Paschim Champaran",
            "Gaya",
            "Kaimur",
            "Nawada"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "How many UNESCO World Heritage site is there in Bihar?",
        "answer": "Two",
        "choices": [
            "Two",
            "One",
            "Three",
            "Four"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which river divides the northern plain area of Bihar into two parts?",
        "answer": "Bagmati",
        "choices": [
            "Bagmati",
            "Ganga",
            "Gandak",
            "Kosi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which one of the following soils in not found in the Northern Gangetic Plain of Bihar?",
        "answer": "Balthar Mitti",
        "choices": [
            "Balthar Mitti",
            "New Alluvial (Khadar)",
            "Marshy Soil",
            "Bal Sundari Mitti"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The most predominant type of soil found in Bihar is",
        "answer": "Alluvial Soil",
        "choices": [
            "Alluvial Soil",
            "Laterite Soil",
            "Yellow & Red Soil",
            "Black Soil"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which river system is primarily responsible for the formation of the alluvial soils in Bihar?",
        "answer": "Ganga",
        "choices": [
            "Ganga",
            "Godavari",
            "Son",
            "Mahanadi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which district of Bihar is known for patches of laterite soil?",
        "answer": "Gaya",
        "choices": [
            "Gaya",
            "Patna",
            "Purnea",
            "Sitamarhi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Red and yellow soils in Bihar are mainly found in:",
        "answer": "South Bihar Plateau region",
        "choices": [
            "South Bihar Plateau region",
            "North Bihar plains",
            "Floodplains of Kosi",
            "Champaran region"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The soil in the Kosi river basin of Bihar is often less fertile due to:",
        "answer": "Sand Deposition",
        "choices": [
            "Sand Deposition",
            "Salinity",
            "Excess Clay",
            "Rocky Texture"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The Harha Valley in Bihar lies between which two geographical features?",
        "answer": "Someshwar Range and Ramnagar Dun",
        "choices": [
            "Someshwar Range and Ramnagar Dun",
            "Chotanagpur Plateau and Rajmahal Hills",
            "Kaimur Hills and Rohtas Plateau",
            "Gandak River and Koshi River"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The Harha Valley is also known as:",
        "answer": "Doon Valley",
        "choices": [
            "Doon Valley",
            "Terai Basin",
            "Malwa Plateau",
            "Barind Region"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The Harha River is located in which physical division of Bihar?",
        "answer": "Northwestern Shivalik–Terai Region",
        "choices": [
            "Northwestern Shivalik–Terai Region",
            "Middle Ganga Plain",
            "Chhotanagpur Region",
            "Eastern Coastal Plain"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which of the following rivers does not make boundary between Uttar Pradesh and Bihar?",
        "answer": "Son",
        "choices": [
            "Son",
            "Gandak",
            "Ghagra",
            "Karmanasha"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "From which river water comes in Triveni Canal?",
        "answer": "Gandak",
        "choices": [
            "Gandak",
            "Son",
            "Kosi",
            "Mayurkashi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where does the Budhi Gandak river meet the Ganga river?",
        "answer": "Khagaria",
        "choices": [
            "Khagaria",
            "Badalaghat",
            "Kursela",
            "Maner"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Mohana and Lilajan rivers are related to which river?",
        "answer": "Falgu River",
        "choices": [
            "Falgu River",
            "Kosi River",
            "Chandan River",
            "Kiul River"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "With which district is Chandan river related to in Bihar?",
        "answer": "Banka",
        "choices": [
            "Banka",
            "Nawada",
            "Buxar",
            "Madhubani"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where is Baraila Salim Ali-Zubba Sahni Bird Sanctuary located?",
        "answer": "Vaishali",
        "choices": [
            "Vaishali",
            "Bhagalpur",
            "Begusarai",
            "Rohtas"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "When is Bihar Prithvi Divas celebrated?",
        "answer": "9th August",
        "choices": [
            "9th August",
            "22nd April",
            "5th June",
            "2nd October"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The Someshwar Range is a part of which major Himalayan foothills?",
        "answer": "Shiwaliks",
        "choices": [
            "Shiwaliks",
            "Karakoram Range",
            "Pir Panjal Range",
            "Lesser Himalayas"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which district of Bihar is home to the Someshwar Range?",
        "answer": "West Champaran",
        "choices": [
            "West Champaran",
            "East Champaran",
            "Sitamarhi",
            "Sheohar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "What is the name of the highest peak in the Someshwar Range, which is also the highest point in Bihar?",
        "answer": "Someshwar Fort",
        "choices": [
            "Someshwar Fort",
            "Rajgir Peak",
            "Kaimur Fort",
            "Girnar Peak"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The Someshwar Range forms a natural border between Bihar and which neighboring country?",
        "answer": "Nepal",
        "choices": [
            "Nepal",
            "Bangladesh",
            "Bhutan",
            "China"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which river flows through the Valmiki National Park and forms the western boundary of the Valmiki Wildlife Sanctuary, located near the Sumeshwar Range?",
        "answer": "Gandak",
        "choices": [
            "Gandak",
            "Kosi",
            "Ganga",
            "Son"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "What type of rocks primarily make up the Sumeshwar Range?",
        "answer": "Sedimentory Rocks",
        "choices": [
            "Sedimentory Rocks",
            "Igneous Rock",
            "Metamorphic Rock",
            "Granite Rocks"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Apart from the Sumeshwar Range, which of the following is another major hill range in Bihar?",
        "answer": "Vindhya",
        "choices": [
            "Vindhya",
            "Aravalli",
            "Satupura Range",
            "Eastern Ghats"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The Valmiki National Park is contiguous with which national park in Nepal?",
        "answer": "Chitwan National Park",
        "choices": [
            "Chitwan National Park",
            "Bardiya National Park",
            "Sagarmatha National Park",
            "Langtang National Park"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The Kanti Thermal Power Station is located near which city in Bihar?",
        "answer": "Muzaffarpur",
        "choices": [
            "Muzaffarpur",
            "Bhagalpur",
            "Gaya",
            "Patna"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which power plant, located in the Bhagalpur district of Bihar, is a major source of power for the eastern region of India?",
        "answer": "Kahalgaon Super Thermal Power Station",
        "choices": [
            "Kahalgaon Super Thermal Power Station",
            "Nabinagar Super Thermal Power Project",
            "Muzaffarpur Thermal Power Station",
            "Barauni Thermal Power Station"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "In which district of Bihar is the Nabinagar Super Thermal Power Project located?",
        "answer": "Aurangabad",
        "choices": [
            "Aurangabad",
            "Bhagalpur",
            "Muzaffarpur",
            "Begusarai"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The Barauni Thermal Power Station, one of the oldest power plants in Bihar, is located in which district?",
        "answer": "Begusarai",
        "choices": [
            "Begusarai",
            "Gaya",
            "Supaul",
            "Muzaffarpur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where is NTPC Barh Super Thermal Power Plant located in Bihar?",
        "answer": "Patna",
        "choices": [
            "Patna",
            "Begusarai",
            "Bhagalpur",
            "Aurangabad"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which city in Bihar is famously known as the 'Silk City' for its textile manufacturing?",
        "answer": "Bhagalpur",
        "choices": [
            "Bhagalpur",
            "Muzaffarpur",
            "Gaya",
            "Patna"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The famous Tussar silk is a specialty of which city in Bihar?",
        "answer": "Bhagalpur",
        "choices": [
            "Bhagalpur",
            "Nalanda",
            "Vaishali",
            "Darbhanga"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The silk industry in Bihar primarily focuses on which aspect of textile production?",
        "answer": "Weaving and Manufacturing",
        "choices": [
            "Weaving and Manufacturing",
            "Spinning & Reeling",
            "Finishing & Dyeing",
            "Sericulture (rearing Silkwroms)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where were the two main manufacturing plants of Bharat Wagon & Engineering Company Limited (BWEL) located in Bihar?",
        "answer": "Muzaffarpur & Mokama",
        "choices": [
            "Muzaffarpur & Mokama",
            "Bhagalpur & Nalanda",
            "Darbhanga & Arrah",
            "Patna & Gaya"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The Electric Locomotive Factory in Madhepura is a joint venture between Indian Railways and which company?",
        "answer": "Alstom SA",
        "choices": [
            "Alstom SA",
            "Bombardier",
            "General Electric",
            "Siemens"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Dalmianagar, a major industrial hub in its prime, is located in which district of Bihar?",
        "answer": "Rohtas",
        "choices": [
            "Rohtas",
            "Kaimur",
            "Patna",
            "Gaya"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Dalmianagar in Bihar is known for",
        "answer": "Cement",
        "choices": [
            "Cement",
            "Silk",
            "Leather",
            "Jute"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "What river is Dalmiyanagar situated on the banks of?",
        "answer": "Son",
        "choices": [
            "Son",
            "Ganga",
            "Falgu",
            "Punpun"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Mica, a mineral used in electrical insulation and electronics, is primarily found in which two districts of Bihar?",
        "answer": "Nawada & Jamui",
        "choices": [
            "Nawada & Jamui",
            "Patna & Bhojpur",
            "Rohtas & Kaimur",
            "Jamui & Banka"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Limestone, a crucial raw material for the cement industry, is abundant in which part of Bihar?",
        "answer": "Southern Plateau region",
        "choices": [
            "Southern Plateau region",
            "Ganga Basin",
            "Eastern foothills of Himalayas",
            "Northern Plains"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which district of Bihar is a known source of Quartzite, a mineral used in the production of glass and ceramics?",
        "answer": "Munger",
        "choices": [
            "Munger",
            "Kishanganj",
            "Sheohar",
            "Arwal"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which mineral found in Bihar is used in the manufacture of ceramics and is often referred to as 'kaolin'?",
        "answer": "China Clay",
        "choices": [
            "China Clay",
            "Dolomite",
            "Steatite",
            "Bauxite"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The Amjhore area in the Rohtas district is particularly famous for the mining of which mineral?",
        "answer": "Pyrites",
        "choices": [
            "Pyrites",
            "Mica",
            "Bauxite",
            "Gold"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Steatite, also known as soapstone, which is used for talcum powder and carvings, is found in which of the following regions of Bihar?",
        "answer": "Gaya",
        "choices": [
            "Gaya",
            "Supaul",
            "Vaishali",
            "Purnia"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Gold deposits have been discovered in which district of Bihar, leading to significant geological interest?",
        "answer": "Jamui",
        "choices": [
            "Jamui",
            "Rohtas",
            "Lakhisarai",
            "Saharsa"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which district in Bihar is home to the Barauni Refinery?",
        "answer": "Begusarai",
        "choices": [
            "Begusarai",
            "Munger",
            "Patna",
            "Gaya"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The Barauni Refinery was established as a result of a collaboration between India and which other country?",
        "answer": "Soviet Union",
        "choices": [
            "Soviet Union",
            "United Kingdom",
            "France",
            "United States"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which type of soil is predominantly found in the northern part of Bihar and is known for its high fertility?",
        "answer": "Alluvial Soil",
        "choices": [
            "Alluvial Soil",
            "Piedmont Swamp Soil",
            "Red & Yellow Soil",
            "Karail-Kewal Soil"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The older alluvial soil found in Bihar's plains is locally known by which of the following names?",
        "answer": "Bangur",
        "choices": [
            "Bangur",
            "Balthar",
            "Tal",
            "Khadar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The 'Tal' soil, found in the southern Gangetic plain of Bihar, is best suited for the cultivation of which crop?",
        "answer": "Wheat & Pulses",
        "choices": [
            "Wheat & Pulses",
            "Rice (Dhan)",
            "Sugarcane",
            "Tea"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Karail-Kewal soil is a type of soil that is dark in color and has a heavy texture. Where is this soil primarily found?",
        "answer": "Southern part of Gangetic plain",
        "choices": [
            "Southern part of Gangetic plain",
            "Transitional zone between the plains and plateau",
            "Mountainous region of state",
            "Northernmost districts of Bihar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The Red and Yellow soils in Bihar are found in the southern plateau region. What is the primary reason for their color?",
        "answer": "Oxidation of Iron Compounds",
        "choices": [
            "Oxidation of Iron Compounds",
            "High content of phosphorus and potash",
            "Presence of humus and other organic matter",
            "Low moisture retention and sandy texture"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which of the following soil types is formed by wind-blown deposits, is light in texture, and is found along the banks of the Ganges River?",
        "answer": "Bal Sundari Soil",
        "choices": [
            "Bal Sundari Soil",
            "Bhat Soil",
            "Doab Soil",
            "Teri Soil"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The soils in the floodplains of the Kosi River are often sandy and have a high pH. What is this soil type called?",
        "answer": "Dhira Soil",
        "choices": [
            "Dhira Soil",
            "Talsand Soil",
            "Tari Soil",
            "Bhangar Soil"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Soil in Bihar is often deficient in which two essential nutrients for plant growth?",
        "answer": "Nitrogen and Phosphorus",
        "choices": [
            "Nitrogen and Phosphorus",
            "Potash and Calcium",
            "Sulphur and Manganese",
            "Iron and Zinc"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which soil type in Bihar is characterized by its reddish-yellow color, is found in the transitional zone between the plains and the plateau, and is often less fertile?",
        "answer": "Balthar Soil",
        "choices": [
            "Balthar Soil",
            "Red and Yellow Soil",
            "Bangur Soil",
            "Tal Soil"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which state in India is the largest producer of litchi?",
        "answer": "Bihar",
        "choices": [
            "Bihar",
            "Jharkhand",
            "Uttar Pradesh",
            "West Bengal"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which city is famously known as the “Litchi Capital of India”?",
        "answer": "Muzaffarpur",
        "choices": [
            "Muzaffarpur",
            "Bhagalpur",
            "Darbhanga",
            "Patna"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "What is the name of the special variety of litchi from Muzaffarpur that has a GI tag?",
        "answer": "Shahi Litchi",
        "choices": [
            "Shahi Litchi",
            "Purbi Litchi",
            "China Litchi",
            "Deshi Litchi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which of the following is the largest freshwater oxbow lake in Asia and is located in Bihar?",
        "answer": "Kabar Taal (Kanwar Lake)",
        "choices": [
            "Kabar Taal (Kanwar Lake)",
            "Ghogha Lake",
            "Baraila Lake",
            "Kusheshwar Asthan Lake"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which lake in Bihar is a declared bird sanctuary and is famous for attracting a large number of migratory birds during the winter?",
        "answer": "Kusheshwar Asthan Bird Sanctuary",
        "choices": [
            "Kusheshwar Asthan Bird Sanctuary",
            "Baraila Lake",
            "Ghogha Lake",
            "Kanwar Lake"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The Gogra-Barhila wetland, a recognized Ramsar site, is situated in which district of Bihar?",
        "answer": "Saran",
        "choices": [
            "Saran",
            "Begusarai",
            "Darbhanga",
            "Vaishali"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which of the following is a prominent man-made reservoir in Bihar, created for irrigation and power generation?",
        "answer": "Indrapuri Barrage",
        "choices": [
            "Indrapuri Barrage",
            "Ghogha Lake",
            "Kanwar lake",
            "Jal Mandir Lake"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Kusheshwar Asthan, a famous bird sanctuary, is located in which district of Bihar?",
        "answer": "Darbhanga",
        "choices": [
            "Darbhanga",
            "Araria",
            "Madhepura",
            "Katihar"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The 'Ghogha Lake' is an important wetland for migratory birds and is located in which district?",
        "answer": "Bhagalpur",
        "choices": [
            "Bhagalpur",
            "Nalanda",
            "Jamui",
            "Araria"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "The monsoon season in Bihar is primarily influenced by which branch of the Indian Monsoon?",
        "answer": "Bay of Bengal branch",
        "choices": [
            "Bay of Bengal branch",
            "South China Sea branch",
            "Arabian Sea branch",
            "Andaman Sea branch"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which district in Bihar has the highest forest cover by area?",
        "answer": "Kaimur (Bhabua)",
        "choices": [
            "Kaimur (Bhabua)",
            "West Champaran",
            "Jamui",
            "Rohtas"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which wildlife sanctuary is currently being proposed to become Bihar's second tiger reserve?",
        "answer": "Kaimur Wildlife Sanctuary",
        "choices": [
            "Kaimur Wildlife Sanctuary",
            "Bhimbandh Wildlife Sanctuary",
            "Udaipur Wildlife Sanctuary",
            "Gautam Buddha Wildlife Sanctuary"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which wildlife sanctuary is the largest in Bihar by area?",
        "answer": "Kaimur Wildlife Sanctuary",
        "choices": [
            "Kaimur Wildlife Sanctuary",
            "Valmiki National Park",
            "Bhimbandh Wildlife Sanctuary",
            "Nagi Dam Bird Sanctuary"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which major river, known as the 'Sorrow of Bihar,' is infamous for its frequent changes in course and devastating floods?",
        "answer": "Kosi",
        "choices": [
            "Kosi",
            "Son",
            "Gandak",
            "Mahananda"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "At which of the following locations does the Gandak River join the Ganga?",
        "answer": "Sonpur",
        "choices": [
            "Sonpur",
            "Badalaghat",
            "Chhapra",
            "Khagaria"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Which river originates from the Chota Nagpur Plateau and flows into South Bihar?",
        "answer": "Falgu",
        "choices": [
            "Falgu",
            "Son",
            "Mahananda",
            "Bagmati"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharSpecific",
        "question": "Where is Bihar's first inland container depot (ICD) located?",
        "answer": "Bihta (Patna)",
        "choices": [
            "Bihta (Patna)",
            "Purnea",
            "Gaya",
            "Banka"
        ]
    }
]